Shuai Zha – Curriculum Vitae

Address Department of Astronomy,

AlbaNova University Center Stockholm University

SE-106 91 Stockholm SWEDEN

Mobile Phone Email Homepage

+46 732447310 shuai.zha@astro.su.se joshuashzha.github.io

Personal Profile

I am currently a postdoctoral researcher in the Department of Astronomy, Stockholm University, Sweden. I mainly work on developing a hydrodynamics code with neutrino transport to simulate stellar collapse and explosion. I also work on the evolution of super-asymptotic-giant-branch stars as progenitors of electron-capture supernovae.

Position

2019- Postdoctoral researcher, Department of Astronomy, Stockholm University

Education

2015-2019 Ph.D. in Physics - the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Supernovae simulation and stellar evolution

2012-2015 M.Sc. in Physics - Fudan University, Shanghai

 $Sum\mbox{-}frequency\ spectroscopy\ with\ femtosecond\ laser$

2008-2012 B.Sc. in Physics - Fudan University, Shanghai

Publications

July 2019 Evolution of ONeMg Core in Super-AGB Stars towards Electron-Capture Supernovae: Ef-

fects of Updated Electron-Capture Rate

Shuai Zha, Shing-Chi Leung, Toshio Suzuki, Ken'ichi Nomoto

Astrophysical Journal accepted; arXiv:1907.04184

June 2019 Accretion-Induced Collapse of Dark Matter Admixed White Dwarfs - II: Rotation and

Gravitational-wave Signals

Shuai Zha, Shing-Chi Leung, Ming-Chung Chu, Lap-Ming Lin

Astrophysical Journal 883, 13; arXiv:1908.05150

June 2019 Accretion-Induced Collapse of Dark Matter Admixed White Dwarfs - I : Formation of Low-

mass Neutron Stars

Shing-Chi Leung, Shuai Zha, Ming-Chung Chu, Lap-Ming Lin, Ken'ichi Nomoto

Astrophysical Journal 884, 9; arXiv:1908.05102

May 2019 Electron capture rates in ²⁰Ne for a forbidden transition to the ground state of ²⁰F relevant

to final evolution of high density O-Ne-Mg cores

Toshio Suzuki, Shuai Zha, Shing-Chi Leung, Ken'ichi Nomoto

Astrophysical Journal 881, 64; arXiv:1905.10400

Constraints on the chemical enrichment history of the Perseus Cluster of galaxies from Nov 2018 high-resolution X-ray spectroscopy Aurora Simionescu et. al. (36 authors including Shuai Zha) Mon. Notices Royal Astron. Soc., 483, 1701 Gravitational-Wave and Neutrino Signals from Core-Collapse Supernovae with QCD Phase Jan 2018 Transition Shuai Zha, Shing-Chi Leung, Lap-Ming Lin, and Ming-Chung Chu JPS Conf. Proc., 20, 011053 Surface pH and Ion Affinity at the Alcohol-Monolayer/Water Interface Studied by Sum-Jun 2016 Frequency Spectroscopy Yu-Chieh Wen, Shuai Zha, Chuanshan Tian, and Yuen-Ron Shen The Journal of Physical Chemistry C, 120, 28 Unveiling Microscopic Structures of Charged Water Interfaces by Surface-Specific Vibra-Jan 2016 tional Spectroscopy Yu-Chieh Wen, Shuai Zha, Xing Liu, Shanshan Yang, Pan Guo, Guosheng Shi, Haiping Fang, Yuen-Ron Shen, and Chuanshan Tian Phys. Rev. Lett., 116, 016101 Carbon nanodots featuring efficient FRET for two-photon photodynamic cancer therapy Aug 2014 with a low fs laser power density

Seminar talks

Oct. 2018 ASIAA, Lunch talk, Taipei, Taiwan
Evolution of Super-AGB Stars Towards Accretion-Induced Collapse

Jul. 2018 Kavli IPMU, APEC seminar, Tokyo, Japan
Correlated Gravitational-wave and Neutrino Signal from Accretion-Induced Collapse of
White Dwarfs

Jul. 2016 Kavli IPMU, APEC seminar, Tokyo, Japan
Accretion Induced Collapse of White Dwarf and its Possible Signals

Jing Wang, Zehui Zhang, Shuai Zha, Yinyan Zhu, Peiyi Wu, Benjamin Ehrenberg, and

Conference presentations

Ji-Yao Chen

Biomaterials, 35, 9372

May 2019	Oral, Electron-Capture-Initiated Stellar Collapse, Lorentz Center, Leiden, The Netherlands
Nov. 2018	Oral, CoCoNuT Meeting 2018, CEA Saclay, Paris, France
Oct. 2018	Oral, The 8th East Asian Numerical Astrophysics Meeting, NCKU, Tainan, Taiwan
Sep. 2018	Poster, Sixth Annual GMT Community Science Meeting, Honolulu, Hawaii, United States
Feb. 2017	Poster, Quarks and Compact Stars, YITP, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan
Jul. 2016	Oral, 10th JGX Astrophysics Meeting, Xiamen University, Xiamen, Fujian

Research experience

2017-2018 Kavli IPMU, the University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

Collaborative research with Prof. Kon'ichi Nomete on Evolut.

Collaborative research with Prof. Ken'ichi Nomoto on Evolution of Super-AGB stars towards Electron-Capture Supernova

Teaching experience

2015-2019 **Teaching assistant** General Physics, Astronomy, Introduction to Astrophysics

2012-2015 Teaching assistant University Physics, Semiconductor Physics, Nonlinear Optics

Professional Activities

Feb. 2019 Organizer of supernova mini-workshop in CUHK, Hong Kong

Awards

Sep. 2017 Global Scholarship Programme for Research Excellence, CUHK

Sep. 2012 Entrance Scholarship for fresh graduate student, Fudan University

Programming Language

Fortran, C, matlab, Python, LATEX